Episode 19
You don't feel well, why are you here?
Let's go back
Project coordinator and song translator: Nemie
Let's go
I was waiting for you, I wanted to talk
Translators: Nemie, Kaia, tamaramin
I can't
return to your chambers
Beta Editor: Sana
Don't do this to me because of Chae Ryung
She fooled you
She was never sincere with you
I'm fine
Chae Ryung...
was sincere with me
No matter what you say
she was sincere
So what?
Will you trust her more than me?
I want to leave the palace
I want to leave this place
I can't take it anymore...
it's tolerable
What about me?
Do you think I'll let you go?
I will become the darkness
You
And I'll wrap you in myself
you can never leave me
Just for a day, just like that
Stay with me
And I will become the moon
I will be the light for one
Wherever I am, wherever I go, I will come
You are my love, believe me
You're the only one I need so much
I look at you from afar
And I'll turn away again
Here I confess to you alone
With all my strength I
Can you completely abandon your brother and family?
Love, love, love
If you only become my empress...
Can you hear my heart now?
I will make our child crown prince
Koryo will belong to my son
Please find and notify Chae Ryung's family
This is all I have
If they need anything else,
I will do anything to give it to them
You shouldn't do this
I'm worried you'll anger the emperor
She cared about her family even when she was dying
Asked me for help
The Emperor won't mind
Great job
Hello Chi Mon
Chae Ryung died
Really?
You shouldn't be so calm
It's your fault
Mine?
You've apparently gone crazy
You'll regret this
This is how she was treated...
I promise one day you'll regret it
Since becoming the emperor's mistress,
I thought I could do whatever I wanted
- So?
- Mistress?
Your Majesty
Did you call me?
I heard from Chi Mon
I must officially declare you a concubine
There's no need for this
It's better to be called that than a mistress
I don't want to hear it
You will be my wife, second only to the Empress
When your baby is born,
you will be proclaimed second empress
I don't want to leave this place because of the title.
Discuss with Chi Mon what title you want
Your Majesty
You know you can't, so don't be stubborn
Let's not fight
Have you forgotten how long we were apart?
I just want to say that we shouldn't waste our time arguing.
Does he want to read "Fundamentals of Politics in the Zhenguan Era" in its entirety?
I don't know his intentions
I guess I should give him a hawk
So agile that it will be good at hunting
I don't know what he's up to
He wants to go hunting
We need to contribute to this
Brother, you know our 4th brother well
You can't trust him and let your guard down around him
You must cut off his arms and legs
Are you talking about Baek Ah?
He still hangs around that gisaeng
It will be easy to remove him from the emperor
What's holding you back now?
We have already found you a foster family
My mother is waiting to meet you
Is it all because of what happened that time?
I already said that we will free all the slaves from Baekje
This won't happen again
escaped slaves
Why don't the people of Hupakje pay tribute?
Why are they like this? God
Baekje slaves have already set fire to 10 houses
Many members of powerful clans died
We can't just sit back
The clans ask you to send soldiers
If we do this, there will definitely be casualties
Among them there will be not only slaves
If people from other countries join, there will be chaos in Goryeo
First of all, you must protect the clans!
Their lives will be at risk
until the soldiers come to help them
They have already begun to gather an army themselves
You must do this, Your Majesty!
We must save the clans
which are the foundation of this nation
Then
soldiers must carry spears
without sharp tips and wooden swords
I took the throne not long ago.
I want to avoid bloodshed if possible
I believe that 13th Prince Baek Ah will lead them
Baek Ah knows nothing about military and combat activities
Why him?
There are rumors that the Emperor doesn't care about the people of Goryeo,
all he cares about is Prince Baek Ah of Silla and the people from Hubaekje
On top of that, Prince Baek Ah
marries their court lady Hubaekje, adopted by a family from Goryeo
I have already agreed to this
This could also mean that someone close to the emperor is being manipulated by a man from Hubaekje
What funny accusations
These accusations could turn out to be true in a blink of an eye.
It's called "rumors"... or "word of mouth"
I won't allow this
You always walked only with a lute,
how can you handle a sword?
I don't like how Woo Hee is suspected because of her background.
Because of us
you have a lot of problems, your majesty
It would be better if I took a step forward
So that the clans do not interfere,
looks like they need to leave that area
If you take the side of either the clans or the slaves,
this will cause problems
I'm not going to die
If we leave it like this...
the clans will control us,
and the throne will be in danger
I'll be fine
I'm still looking at you from the outside
It seemed to me that you are my love
I kept thinking that you feel the same way
Although you look the other way
Won't you regret it?
Like the wind, like dust
I pretended to be strong
I don't know what could happen to me
You will have a wife, you must survive
I can't catch you and see you
I don't want to become a widow
Do you remember: I love, I love
When I return
I believe there was love, I’ll call it fate
let's get married
And I can only answer you:
You are mine...
life partner
Hold me if I'm swinging
Right now I really want to not be associated with Hubaekje
my love
I am yours with all my heart
Out of the way!
Forward!
There's something here!
I, the Emperor of Goryeo, want to promise the people of Baekje
Slaves will not be touched
To resolve this issue,
I will weigh everything carefully and make the right decision
People who were forcibly enslaved during the war will be freed
Foreigners who were turned into slaves
will be restored to their position
All this will be strictly observed
Slaves who were forcibly taken away will be returned to their homelands
They will be exempt from paying tribute for a certain time
Down with the difference in attitude towards people depending on their origin
You can even become officials
All of you will be subjects of Goryeo
They always lie about the same thing!
- Yeah!
- You can't fool us! No!
They take us for dogs and pigs!
Let's. Forward!
Yes!
You are in exile, why are you here?
Lost my mind
Tell the emperor to do as he pleases, I'm not afraid of anything
I told you he would sentence you to death
He could have sent me
Please don't die
You may come back wounded
but don't die
I can't stand it
Did you receive what Hae Soo asked me to give you?
A hairpin?
Yes
But I don't know what it means
because she didn't send the letter...
She also asked to convey:
"I want it"
"I want this"?
Did Hae Soo really say that?
Yes, that's what she said
"Hae Soo
really wants this"
I asked you to tell me
I don't know what she wants
Help her
I don't know what will happen to me
You must remain a good friend to her.
And for the emperor too
It's hard for him
Should you worry about others now?
No one even came to see you off
What about that courtier from the gisaeng house?
I told Woo Hee that it would be better if she didn't come.
Please take care of yourself brother
Later Three Korean States: Reunification of Goryeo, Baekje and Silla
Woo Hee...
Princess! This is Princess Woo Hee!
Princess Woo Hee, be careful! Get off there
You can't stand there
Woo Hee!
Stop
You won't...?
No need
Turn away
Look away!
If you see
you'll never forget
Woo Hee!
I thought I could forget about everything and move on with my life
I wanted to abandon my parents
But I can't turn away from my people who consider me a mother
I don't think I can live like this
The flower will fall to the ground, it withered
Goryeo and Baekje
Gyung Hwon and Wang Gun
Their sins...
He will be all alone, so sad
I will pay for them with my life
Perhaps this is the reason I was born
The sky will lose its stars, it will instantly become sad
Beck A,
Woo Hee!
i love you
Only you
my life partner
And suddenly it starts crying like a little rain
It feels like a flower blooms and then withers
Tell me with the wind, please
With the appearance of snow, all dreams will come true
With all my heart I believe so, they are sincere
Do you know my heart that it always waits like this?
In order not to forget about her, you must not destroy yourself
Why didn't she tell me?
If so, come back
I must have made her like this
Come to think of it, I was too greedy
Subjects of the fallen nation and former gisaeng,
orphan
I knew about her past
I was so proud to love her
It was narcissistic
I didn't try to understand Woo Hee's true feelings
Why was she sad, why was she unhappy?
"Why is your smile so short-lived?"
I never asked her about this
It was fleeting love
In this situation, Woo Hee behaved badly
We gave her our hearts
And she
wasn't selfish enough
She's bad
The Emperor knew about this
Really?
Your face doesn't look good
I will send a doctor to you, you will be treated
Woo Hee asked to post that decree
That means you made a deal with her, right?
I didn't know she was going to die
She said I could save you if I wrote it
It all happened when I found out that she was Princess Hubaekje
I wanted to save you
It was like grabbing a rotten rope, but I wrote it anyway
I didn't know it would turn out this way, but even if I had known...
the same thing would happen
For me
you are more important
I know this
I understand this
but it's hard for me to accept it
It's hard to be by your side
Don't do this
I...
was wrong
No, I
I'm sorry I couldn't protect you
Please live long and healthy,
brother
Beck Ah!
Beck A!!!
Are you sure of your decision?
Completely
You mentioned you were going hunting
I have a hunting hawk for you
I really like hunting hawks
This is an indicator of brotherly love
They say brotherly love is the foundation of humanity
Wow! That's why brothers are the best in the world
Family harmony means
harmony in the country, don’t you think?
Isn't that a dead hawk?
The Emperor was given a dead hawk?
You cursed the emperor!
We can't leave it like this!
Your Majesty...
This is a misunderstanding
Something happened while carrying the hawk...
You brought it yourself, who do you blame?
Did you want to curse the emperor?
So this is treason?
Everyone understands that this is so!
It's true, Your Majesty
Your Majesty, you misunderstood!
I was set up, Your Majesty!
If this is treason,
you must pay for it with your life
Empress!
Have you come?
Uka was framed, he could die
I heard he made a serious mistake that can't be undone
You must save your brother
I refuse
Your Majesty...
I can't get involved in politics just to cover up my brother's crimes.
His crimes are very serious
The elders from Hwangju are watching me closely
Don't expect much from me
"Only"?
You use the word "only"
when it comes to your brother's life?!
I am now the empress
I value my family and don't want to lose my brother
But I have to take a broader view
You must let me go, mother
Sorry Uka
I'm sure he was framed
Let him live
Your Majesty
Don't you know you can't kneel?
You may lose the ability to walk, get up
You said you wouldn't touch your brothers
Don't do this
I know you care about princes
But I don't like that you came to me and begged for his salvation on your knees
- Get up
- The Man Who Killed the Hawk -
it was you, Your Majesty
You did this on purpose, putting Uk's life in danger
So what?
Shouldn't I have done that?
Wook killed our elder brother and Eun.
He chased Baek Ah
Tried to kill me and divide us
- He’s such a person!
-If you kill anyone else,
it will definitely come back to you
If you are so cruel in your punishments,
everyone will consider you an enemy
In the future...
I wouldn't want you to be remembered as a bloody ruler
Okay. I'll let him live
He will be punished by exile to his hometown
He will not be allowed to take a single step out of his home
He wanted to take over Goryeo,
but now his home will become his whole world
In that house... he will suffocate
He'll have to live there until his heart rots
If you think about it
this punishment suits him better,
than immediate execution
Do you have time to play with flowers?
You're disgusting
I heard about Uke
I know what you're going through
on this matter, Your Majesty
Since childhood he never refused me
I'm curious if I ruined his life
I'm very worried about this
I betrayed him to become empress
I wanted the two of us to rule this palace
I pushed him away too much
However...
It's not me who completely changed my brother
It was you
- What?
- I heard from my brother,
what did you tell him to beware of the 4th prince
You told him not to get in Prince Wang So's way or he might die.
This is because
what did I tell him to be wary of the 4th prince?
After he heard this, he believed that the 4th prince would become emperor
He had feelings for you
What he hated most was that you saw the future emperor in another man.
I put pressure on Uka
But it was you who became the hammer that hammered the nail
It all started with you
I decided to kill my brothers and become emperor
All because of you...
You helped Seo hide his scar so he could take my place.
Because he took what belonged to me...
Beware of Prince Wang So
Avoid him. You can't stop him
and if you try...
You will all die
It's all my fault
If only you hadn't told him to beware of the 4th prince
If you hadn't intervened and said that the 4th prince would be emperor
Uk would not have changed beyond recognition
You ruined everything
What's even more shameful is that you're still alive
This is my favorite, Su
And white tea is mine
Is it all my fault?
Draw it so I look exactly like you
It is necessary that, looking at the picture, people get the impression that they are looking at me
I thought we would draw something
what will you look like when you get old?
You don't sit on your throne
People won't know whether you're an emperor or a prince
They will be confused
I'm very young now. Why hang a picture after my death?
I want to give it to someone
You can't! It is forbidden!
I have come to see His Majesty
And you boldly ignore the imperial decrees
You probably dream about death
I came because I need your permission, Your Majesty.
You wouldn't have accepted me if I had warned you in advance
This is the decree that the late emperor left
I consent to the marriage of Prince Jeong and Court Lady Hae Soo
Thanks to you, the border has calmed down
Before I leave, I'll give you whatever you want as a reward.
Anything I want?
If it's not a throne, you can call it anything
If so...
there is something that I have been wanting for a very long time
It's fake
This is a lie
You have ascended to the throne thanks to the last decree of the late Emperor, Your Majesty
How can you treat his decrees in this way?
You can compare this document with others written by the late emperor
You will be convinced that he wrote it
Even if it's not fake, I won't allow it
You can't marry Hae Soo
Since the late emperor has given his consent, there is nothing to stop me
There's no one in this place
who wouldn't know about our relationship
Do you still want to marry her?
Stop this nonsense
Hae Soo is neither an empress nor an official imperial concubine.
She's not your wife either
There's no reason why she can't marry me
I also informed the ministers about this
I said that I am waiting for your permission for our marriage
Chi Mon
Punish Prince Jeong for violating the expulsion order...
Hae Soo wants it
What?
You can ask her
Hae Soo wants to marry me
This soap was made recently, right?
It breaks easily
For wives, use a floral scent,
and herbs and mint for the emperor and princes
Okay
Jeong says
that he will marry you
He has permission from the late emperor to marry you
Did you know about this?
When did he receive this permission?
September, Year of the Monkey
When he returned after
how he won the battle against the Khitans in Khwai
Jeong said you want it too
I know it's not true
- I can declare that this is a fake...
- I want this
It is a great crime to go against the wishes of the late emperor.
If you don't agree to this, someone will definitely
will challenge your right to sit on the throne
When we are not together, we always passionately desire each other
My heart breaks just thinking about you
But now...
When I can watch you every day...
Sometimes I even despise you
Do you despise?
If we continue like this,
absolutely certain, one day only contempt and disgust will remain
I don't want this
I prefer to leave now
I will never allow this
People are starting to suspect you of the right to inherit the throne, but you don’t care?!
You made me turn my back on my family and brother
But you yourself can’t refuse Hae Soo?
That's right
I won't let Hae Soo go
How long will you continue to say this?
Let's wait and see
You may lose your throne
I won't let this happen
You can climb
The Emperor has decided to spare your life
I hide my tears deep inside
What if people start to suspect you too?
I want to forget everything about you
This is not because
that you still have feelings for me
It's time for us to leave the fate that brought us together
You know I would do this for anyone who was in your shoes
Even though we will have to live in tears
The Emperor knows it too
As if a free wind will carry you away
Forget everything
I kept looking for the way to you, but I never found it
And about the throne and about me
If you don't leave this place,
you can't avoid suffering
I couldn’t catch the fate that was moving away from me
you
must give up first
So I'll let you go completely
Looking at your footprints when you leave me
Now I couldn’t hold back my tears
I was like a fallen petal
I was sad because I had to end it all like this
And if we meet again one day
Then we won’t say goodbye to you
Love
mine
You have to help me brother
Do you have something to tell me?
The Empress desperately begged me for this
So I made an exception
Your Majesty, please wait outside
Brother
I can't ask for anything else
Please listen to the end of what he has to say.
I...
I have to confess about my relationship with Hae Soo
Hae Soo?
Looks like there's something you still don't know about, Your Majesty.
I thought I should tell you about this
The two of us...
promised each other to marry
Do you seriously want to die?
It was long before she became your woman
Su...
was my man
I found out why you were so worried about Uka
Why did you get down on your knees and beg for him?
Now I know
That bracelet you've been wearing for so long
secret meetings in Damiwon...
Is this true?
Did you really want to marry Wook?
Yes
You told me that you had a loved one...
Was this person Uk?
Yes it was him
I like another person
- Beck A?
- No, not Baek A
I'll take her back
If someone sees you two together, rumors will start
Su!
Nothing here belongs to you
Neither Yong Hwa nor Hae Soo
They are mine
Your Majesty!
You said you wouldn't hurt
harm to your brothers
Then instead of this just lie to me
Tell me it's a misunderstanding and that Wook is lying to me!
Then everything will be the same for us
We promised...
don't lie to each other
How could you do this?
Why did you hurt me this way?
Why, of all people, Uk?!
He was always in your heart
Your Majesty...
Don't touch me!
From today...
I will never see you again
Will you hear him?
The same voice that is in such a hurry to confess
Are you still listening?
Can you hear my heart?
How raindrops settled on the window
Also my mind is consumed by you
Need you
I miss you
It was enough to give it up once
I know they say you have to give up something to protect your position.
But if you leave her like this, you will lose not only her, but also yourself.
I didn't leave her
Will you hear him?
The same voice that is in such a hurry to confess
Su...
abandoned me
Are you still listening?
Can you hear my heart?
How raindrops settled on the window
Also my mind is consumed by you
Bring it here
Need you
We became friends by drinking with each other
therefore, when parting, they should drink a cup
Need you
I miss you
If I had any idea about Jeong's plan,
I wouldn't help you so easily
I didn't know either
He said he knew how to leave the palace.
That's all I knew
You don't like this wedding either
Then you should give it up
I don't like the idea of this marriage
But this is the only way I can leave the palace
So I'll do it
For that matter, I wanted
for you to stay with my brother
Why are you trying to leave him
knowing that you can't forget?
There's too much blood in our relationship
I thought I could stop it
Will you hear him?
But I was wrong
The same voice that is in such a hurry to confess
I'm not sure I can continue
stay nearby without interfering
I don't know everything about your relationship
Are you still listening?
Can you hear my heart?
It was a real blessing for me to become your friend
How raindrops settled on the window
Thanks to Ms. He, we have such a wonderful relationship.
Also my mind is consumed by you
Don't let yourself get sick from grief
Need you
I miss you
You have to go
If you're late, I don't know what I'll do
- What do the guards do?
- Prince Baek Ah
Thank you
I didn't do it with good intentions
If you didn't know that I want to leave,
you would never say that
Jeong...
will be good to you
Please take care of yourself
Since you're about to leave,
cut off all the threads that bind you
Forget everything that happened
Think only about the future
Only about this
Su
I think you understand me
When I see you I
I can’t breathe, I’m timid
It's as if everything in the world has stopped
Now you have to go
If I pass by like a breeze,
you won't even notice
My heart is all given to you
But loving you is very painful for me
Our common destiny
And so sad
ended
I need to cross you out of my heart
so hard
Don't forget, please!
That eternal love of mine
You burn with your gaze
As if you know everything yourself
About what's on my heart
Even if I want to, I can’t leave
Holds the memories
Even when you and I are not around
But loving you is very painful for me
And so sad
I need to cross you out of my heart
so hard
If I hadn't met him,
Don't forget, please!
I wouldn't miss him
That eternal love of mine
If I didn't know him,
I wouldn't even think about him at all
If we weren't together,
I wouldn't have to leave
If you're late, it's okay
If I didn't value him so much,
I wouldn't have so many memories
By the will of fate
Suddenly I will be able to meet you!
If I didn't love him...
we wouldn't have to give up on each other
If we hadn't encountered him,
And it’s still just as difficult for me to forget you
we would never be together
It's so hard for me
Perhaps...
This dream is bad, when I remember, I cry
If I hadn't met you at all...
always
I believe once upon a time
how I want to love
I can
Thanks for watching with us!
Release group MANIA
http://doramamania.mybb.ru
http://vk.com/doramamania
But loving you is very painful for me
And so sad
I need to cross you out of my heart
so hard
Don't forget...